Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Records 1972.0001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Records
1882-1973
1888-1920
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1972.0001
33.9 Linear Feet
The records of the Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station provide information on one of the oldest agricultural experiment and research stations in the United States. The records provide substantial information on the early years of the Experiment Station from 1888 to 1920. The majority of the records consist of correspondence to and from the executive and administrative staff of the station and local farmers and business organizations interested in obtaining information about the station's experiments and research findings.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Storrs Agricultural Experiement Station provide information on one of the oldest agricultural experiment and research stations in the United States. The records provide substantial information on the early years of the Experiment Station from 1888 to 1920.
The records provide valuable insight into the relations between the station and the farming communities in Connecticut, the interactions between agricultural stations and the relationship of the station to the state and federal government. The records also describe the agricultural problems of the times, the solutions and suggestions that were offered, and many of the farming implements and methods that were used in Connecticut during the period covered by the materials.
The records span the first sixty years of the experiment station's history (1888-1950), but the bulk of the records cover the period from 1888-1920. The majority of the records consist of correspondence to and from the executive and administrative staff of the station and local farmers and business organizations interested in obtaining information about the station's experiments and research findings. Significant correspondents include: W. O. Atwater, W. H. Leslie, F. E. Singleton, Clarence Atkins, Fred Chadwick, C. S. Phelps and W. B. Young. The records also contain detailed records of the station's financial condition from 1888 to 1899. The records do not contain the actual research findings or publications and bulletins of the Experiment Station.
History
The creation of an agricultural experiment station in Connecticut was first suggested by Professor Wilbur Olin Atwater of Wesleyan University in an address before the State Board of Agriculture in December 1873. Due to Atwater's persuasive powers, the Connecticut General Assembly appropriated $5,600 for the establishment of a temporary, two-year experiment station at Wesleyan University. The station, the first of its kind in America, was started in 1875 with Atwater as its director.
In March 1877, the General Assembly granted $5,000 annually for the creation of a permanent agricultural experiment station at Yale University, then the land grant college of Connecticut. The station was established at the Sheffield Scientific School of Yale in New Haven. Its first director was Professor Samuel Johnson of Yale.
In March 1877, Congress passed the Hatch Act which authorized to each state a grant of $15,000 for the creation of agricultural experiment stations in connection with the land grant colleges. Both Yale University and the Storrs Agricultural School, created in 1881, claimed the grant as the legitimate land grant college in Connecticut. The Storrs Agricultural School's claim was supported by the Connecticut State Grange. The Connecticut General Assembly settled the dispute by splitting the grant between the two claimants.
The Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station was formally established in April 1888, with Professor W. O. Atwater of Wesleyan University (Class of 1865) as its director. The purpose of the station was to conduct research and experiments to further agricultural progress. The results of investigations were published in the bulletins which were made available to Connecticut residents upon request. The station was directed from Wesleyan University. Field experiements were conducted at the Storrs Agricultural School, while laboratory experiements were conducted at the chemistry lab at Wesleyan University.
The General Assembly finally granted an annual appropriation of $1,800 for the Storrs Experiment Station in 1895. Professor Atwater remained the director until 1903 when he resigned and the station was reorganized under the sole control of the Storrs Agricultural College, completely severing its ties with Wesleyan University.
In 1912, the Connecticut Agricultural School at Yale and the Storrs Experiment Station were joined under the direction of Dr. E. H. Jenkins of Yale. The purpose of this joint directorship was to ensure harmony of purpose and to prevent duplication of effort. Professor Jenkins remained the director of the station until 1922, when he was succeeded by Professor William L. Slate, Jr., a Professor of Agronomy at the Connecticut Agricultural School. Professor Slate served as director until 1949. Members of the Station staff devoted the majority of their time to research while others taught and conducted research depending upon the needs of the Station, In 1925, Congress passed the Purnell Act which granted to Connecticut an annual sum of $60,000 in support of its two experiment stations. The Connecticut Agricultural School specialized primarily in plant work, while the Storrs Experiment Station focused on animal industry.
The achievements of the Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station during its first fifty years of existence were notable. Investigations were conducted in numerous areas such as poultry disease and breeding, animal parasites, calf-feeding, pasture management and other subjects. The station was the first to describe and classify the bacteria of milk and milk products. It contributed greatly to the knowledge of the role of legumes in soil fertility, helped to establish practices for the feeding and management of dairy cattle and it worked out the correct practices for the incubation of eggs. Measures for controlling stomach worm in sheep were also developed at the Station.
Custodial History
The records of the Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station were given to the Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station by the Olin Library of Wesleyan University on 28 June 1966. The records were then transferred to the University of Connecticut Library Special Collections Department. In 1973, the records were removed from Special Collections due to lack of storage space and placed in the College of Agriculture vault.
Provenance and Acquisition
The records were transferred from the College of Agriculture to the University Archives in 1981.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Archives (institutions); Manuscripts (document genre); Agricultural colleges; Reports; Correspondence; Connecticut (state); Publications (documents); University of Connecticut; Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station; Storrs Agricultural College (Conn.); Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
- Series I: Correspondence, 1897-1920
  Scope and Content Note
  [Subjects include: Correspondence to and from companies and organizations: A.B. Ansbacher and Co.; Ansbacher Insecticide Co, Inc.; American Association for the Advancement of Science; American Coal Products Company; American Cooperative Creameries Association; American Express Company; American Farm-Management Association; American Flax Fibre & Linen Corp.; American Milling Company; American Hardware Corporation.
  Correspondence to and from individuals: Pres. Charles Lewis Beach, Charles M. Jarvis, Pres. Rufus W. Stimson, L.A. Prof. Clinton, Francis G. Benedict, James S. Judd, Frank Avery, Prof. H.J. Baker, Prof. William L. Slate, E.H. Jenkins, Dir. H.J. Baker.
  Correspondence with farms and experiment stations: Middletown, Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station; Vermont Agricultural Experiment Station (Burlington, VT.); Valentine Farm; Snow Farm; Whitney Farm.
  Agricultural subjects discussed in correspondence: sulfate of ammonia as pesticide; camembert cheese (Charles M. Jarvis); shropshire sheep; winter vetch; alfalfa hay; poultry testing; crop planting; pigs; white pine blister; model farms.
  Fliers, publications, and Ephemera on: "The Fourth Annual Meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Agricultural Teaching, November 11, 1913" (schedule of events); "Potato Scab and its Prevention" (flier); "Farm Estimate for quarter July-Sept. 1908;" "Practical Agriculture."
  General Subjects, Storrs, Connecticut, University of Connecticut, University of Connecticut History, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Storrs Agricultural School.
  - A. B. Ansbacher and Co., 1912-1915; 1972.0001\SeriesI:Correspondence\Box1:1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Agricultural experiment stations; Correspondence; Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
  - A. B. Dick Company, 1904; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Correspondence; Agricultural experiment stations; Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
  - A. B. Farquhar Company Ltd., 1904-1908; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Correspondence; Agricultural experiment stations; Storrs (inhabited place); Connecticut (state); Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
  - A. H. Andrews Co., 1913-1914; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A. T. Ferrell Co., 1914; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A - Abrams, 1902-1919; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Abbott, Louise W., 1908-1910; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ackerman, J. H., 1908-1909; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ac - Ad, 1904-1918; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Adam, J. S., 1903-1907; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Adams, James F., 1910-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Adams Act, 1906; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Adams Express Co., 1902-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:13; Adams Express Company (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Adams, Leslie L., 1903-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:14 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Adler Color and Chemical Works, 1906-1909; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:15 (Box 1, Folder 15, Folder 15 [39153019696196])
  - Ag - Alv, 1903-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:16 (Box 1, Folder 16, Folder 16 [39153019696204])
  - Alabama Agricultural Experiment Station, 1910-1915; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:17 (Box 1, Folder 17, Folder 17 [39153019696212])
    Correspondence; Agricultural experiment stations; Alabama; Storrs (inhabited place); Connecticut (state); Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
  - Albany Hardware Specialty Manufacturing Co., 1907; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:18 (Box 1, Folder 18, Folder 18 [39153019696220])
  - Allen, J. Z., Watertown Public Schools, 1910; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:19 (Box 1, Folder 19, Folder 19 [39153019696238])
    Correspondence; Agricultural experiment stations; Storrs (inhabited place); Connecticut (state); Watertown (inhabited place); Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
  - Allen, Rufus J., 1908; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:20 (Box 1, Folder 20, Folder 20 [39153019696246])
  - Allerton, Josephine (Mrs. George M.), 1909; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:21 (Box 1, Folder 21, Folder 21 [39153019696253])
  - Allis-Chalmers Co., 1917; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:22 (Box 1, Folder 22, Folder 22 [39153019696261])
  - Allyn, Gurdon S., 1910-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:23 (Box 1, Folder 23, Folder 23 [39153019696279])
  - Alsop, J. W., 1914-1917; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:24 (Box 1, Folder 24, Folder 24 [39153019696287])
  - Altamont Stock Farm (G. Howard Davison), 1906-1907; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:25 (Box 1, Folder 25, Folder 25 [39153019696295])
  - Am - An, 1902-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:26 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - American Agricultural Chemical Company, 1904-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:27 (Box 1, Folder 27, Folder 27 [39153019696311])
    Correspondence; Storrs (inhabited place); Connecticut (state); Agricultural experiment stations; Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
  - American Association of Farmers' Institute Workers, 1905-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:28 (Box 1, Folder 28, Folder 28 [39153019696329])
  - American Brass Company, 1907-1918; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:29 (Box 1, Folder 29, Folder 29 [39153019696337])
  - American Breeders Association, 1908-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:30 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - American Car Company, 1903-1913; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:31 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - American Cement Post Company, 1904; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:32 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - American Colortype Company, 1913; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:33 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - American Cultivator, 1904-1908; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:34 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - American Cyanamid Company, 1907-1913; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:35 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - American Electrical Works, 1898-1902; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:36 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - American Hardware Corporation (Charles M. Jarvis), 1905-1908; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:37 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - American Hardware Corporation (Charles M. Jarvis), 1907; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:38 (Box 1, Folder 38 [39153019696428])
  - American Harrow Co., 1903-1906; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:39 (Box 1, Folder 39 [39153019696436])
  - American Horticultural Distributing Company, 1908; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:40 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - American Jersey Cattle Club, 1906-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:41 (Box 1, Folder 41 [39153019696451])
  - American Seeding Machine Company, 1906-1914; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:42 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - American Shropshire Registry Association, 1907-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:43 (Box 1, Folder 43 [39153019696477])
  - American Society of Agronomy, 1908-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:44 (Box 1, Folder 44 [39153019696485])
  - American Steel and Wire Company, 1902-1917; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:45 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - American Vacuum Drying Machine Company, 1902; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:46 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Amos D. Bridges Sons, 1913; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:47 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Andover Creamery Co., 1907; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:48 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Ap - Ar, 1902-1917; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:49 (Box 1, Folder 49 [39153019696535])
  - Apothecaries Hall Company, 1907-1918; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:50 (Box 1, Folder 50 [39153019696543])
  - Appel, Fred B, 1909; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:51 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Archibald, James F., 1917; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:52 (Box 1, Folder 52 [39153019696568])
  - Argentina, 1907-1913; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:53 (Box 1, Folder 53 [39153019696576])
    Argentina (nation); Correspondence; Storrs (inhabited place); Connecticut (state); Agricultural experiment stations; Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
  - Arkansas Agricultural Experiment Station, 1909-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:54 (Box 1, Folder 54 [39153019696584])
    Arkansas (state); Correspondence; Storrs (inhabited place); Connecticut (state); Agricultural experiment stations; Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
  - Armstrong, Lee F., 1908-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:55 (Box 1, Folder 55 [39153019696592])
  - Arnold, Ernest M., Banker and Broker, 1906-1907; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:56 (Box 1, Folder 56 [39153019696600])
  - Arnold, Robert H., 1919; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:57 (Box 1, Folder 57 [39153019696618])
  - As - Au, 1904-1919; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:58 (Box 1, Folder 58 [39153019696626])
  - Ashley, Dexter D., 1910-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:59 (Box 1, Folder 59 [39153019696634])
  - Ashley, E.S.S., 1905-1910; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:60 (Box 1, Folder 60 [39153019696642])
  - Aspinwall Manufacturing Company, 1908-1918; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:61 (Box 1, Folder 61 [39153019696659])
  - Association of American Agricultural Colleges and Experiment Stations, 1909-1917; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:62 (Box 1, Folder 62 [39153019696667])
  - Atlantic Blau-gas Company, 1913-1914; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:63 (Box 1, Folder 63 [39153019696675])
  - Atlantic Refrigerating Company, 1897-1898; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:64 (Box 1, Folder 64 [39153019696691])
  - Atwater, C. G., 1909-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:65 (Box 1, Folder 65 [39153019696709])
  - Atwater, W. O., 1900; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:66; Atwater, W. O. (Wilbur Olin), 1844-1907 (Box 1, Folder 66 [39153019696717])
  - Atwell, Virginia, 1908-1909; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:67 (Box 1, Folder 67 [39153019696725])
  - Aulick, A. F., 1918; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:68 (Box 1, Folder 68 [39153019696733])
    Agricultural experiment stations; Correspondence; Storrs (inhabited place); Connecticut (state); Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
  - Austin Engraving Company, 1905-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:69 (Box 1, Folder 69 [39153019696741])
    Storrs (inhabited place); Connecticut (state); Agricultural experiment stations; Correspondence; Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
  - Australia, 1909-1914; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:70 (Box 1, Folder 70 [39153019696758])
    Australia (nation); Storrs (inhabited place); Connecticut (state); Correspondence; Agricultural experiment stations; Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
  - Austria, 1901; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:71 (Box 1, Folder 71 [39153019696766])
    Austria; Storrs (inhabited place); Connecticut (state); Correspondence; Agricultural experiment stations; Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
  - Av - Ay, 1902-1917; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:72 (Box 1, Folder 72 [39153019696774])
  - Avery, Frank (Wapping Creamery), 1894-1896; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:73 (Box 1, Folder 73 [39153019696782])
    Storrs (inhabited place); Connecticut (state); Correspondence; Agricultural experiment stations; Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
  - Ayrmont, 1913; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:74 (Box 1, Folder 74 [39153019696790])
  - B. F. Avery and Sons, 1917; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:75 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Bab - Bah, 1904-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:76 (Box 1, Folder 76 [39153019696816])
  - Bai - Ban, 1902-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:77 (Box 1, Folder 77 [39153019696824])
  - Baker, H. J. - Extension Service, Connecticut Agricultural College, 1915-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:78 (Box 1, Folder 78 [39153019696832])
  - Bancroft's Realty Company, undated; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:79 (Box 1, Folder 79 [39153019696840])
  - Bara - Barton, 1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:80 (Box 1, Folder 80 [39153019696683])
  - Barbados, 1904; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:81 (Box 1, Folder 81 [39153019696857])
  - Barnard, J. F., 1908-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:82 (Box 1, Folder 82 [39153019696865])
  - Barnes, Thornton, 1904; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:83 (Box 1, Folder 83 [39153019696873])
  - Barnes Brothers, 1907-1908; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:84 (Box 1, Folder 84 [39153019696881])
  - Barnhart, John Hendley, 1902; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:85 (Box 1, Folder 85 [39153019696899])
  - Baron de Birsch Agricultural School, 1910; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:86 (Box 1, Folder 86 [39153019696907])
  - Barrett, Arthur D., 1913; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:87 (Box 1, Folder 87 [39153019696915])
  - Barriger, T. B., 1917-1919; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:88 (Box 1, Folder 88 [39153019696923])
  - Barstow, J. P., 1888-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:89 (Box 1, Folder 89 [39153019696931])
  - Bartholomew, W. L., 1888; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:90 (Box 1, Folder 90 [39153019696949])
  - Bas - Bay, 1898-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:91 (Box 1, Folder 91 [39153019696956])
  - Bateman Manufacturing Company, 1903-1909; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:92 (Box 1, Folder 92 [39153019696964])
  - Bates, L. A., 1905-1913; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:93 (Box 1, Folder 93 [39153019696972])
  - Bates, Theodore C., 1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:94 (Box 1, Folder 94 [39153019696980])
  - Bausch & Lomb Optical Company, 1905-1913; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:95 (Box 1, Folder 95 [39153019696998])
  - Beac - Belm, 1904-1918; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:96 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Beach, Charles L., 1901-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:97 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Beach, Charles L., 1912-1916; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:98 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Beach, Charles L., 1917-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:99 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Beacon Foundry and Engineering Company, 1907; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:100 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Beadle, H. A., 1910; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:101 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Beadle, H. H., 1907; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:102 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Beebe, Alfred L., 1914; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:103 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Beech-Nut Packing Company, 1906-1908; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:104 (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Belcher and Taylor Agricultural Tool Company, 1904-1918; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:105 (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Belgium, 1902-1914; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:106 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    Correspondence; Agricultural experiment stations; Storrs (inhabited place); Connecticut (state); Belgium (nation); Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
  - Bemis, Earl, 1907-1908; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:107 (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Bem - Bev, 1903-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box1:108 (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Benedict, A. L., 1908-1918; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Benedict, F. G., 1896-1907; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:2 (Box 2, Folder 2 [39153019697145])
  - Bennet Brothers Company, 1905; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:3 (Box 2, Folder 3 [39153019697152])
  - Bennet, E. R., 1905-1906; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:4 (Box 2, Folder 4 [39153019697160])
  - Benson, Allen M., 1904-1909; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:5 (Box 2, Folder 5 [39153019697178])
  - Berlin, Connecticut State Fair, 1905-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:6 (Box 2, Folder 6 [39153019697186])
  - Bethlehem Grange, 1906-1908; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:7 (Box 1, Folder 7 [39153019697194])
  - Bevan, L. A., 1918-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:8 (Box 2, Folder 8 [39153019697202])
  - Bia - Bit, 1902-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:9 (Box 2, Folder 9 [39153019697210])
  - Biltmore Forest School, 1908; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:10 (Box 2, Folder 10 [39153019697228])
  - Bl, 1907-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:11 (Box 2, Folder 11 [39153019697236])
  - Blake, George M., 1913-1919; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:12 (Box 2, Folder 12 [39153019697244])
  - Blakeslee, A. F., 1895-1919; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:13 (Box-folder 2:13, Box 2, Folder 13 [39153019697251])
  - Blatchford's Calf Meal Factory, 1905; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:14 (Box 2, Folder 14 [39153019697269], Box-folder 2:14)
  - Blodgett and Clapp Company, 1908; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:15 (Box-folder 2:15, Box 2, Folder 15 [39153019697277])
  - Blodgett, M. S., 1907; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:16 (Box 2, Folder 16 [39153019697285], Box-folder 2:16)
  - Blomo Manufacturing Co., 1903-1904; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:17 (Box-folder 2:17, Box 2, Folder 17 [39153019697293])
  - Blue Ribbon Body Company, 1902; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:18 (Box 2, Folder 18 [39153019697301], Box-folder 2:18)
  - Boa - Boy, 1902-1917; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:19 (Box-folder 2:19, Box 2, Folder 19 [39153019697319])
  - Bock, H. A., 1911-1913; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:20 (Box-folder 2:20, Box 2, Folder 20 [39153019697327])
  - Boggs Potato Grader Co., Inc., 1918; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:21 (Box-folder 2:21, Box 2, Folder 21 [39153019697335])
  - Bond, George M., 1894; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:22 (Box 2, Folder 22 [39153019697343], Box-folder 2:22)
  - Bonner - Preston Co., 1904; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:23 (Box-folder 2:23, Box 2, Folder 23 [39153019697350])
  - Borgeson, Axel B., 1910-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:24 (Box 2, Folder 24 [39153019697368], Box-folder 2:24)
  - Botsford, H. E., 1910-1911; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:25 (Box-folder 2:25, Box 2, Folder 25 [39153019697376])
  - Bowker Fertilizer Company, 1903-1914; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:26 (Box-folder 2:26, Box 2, Folder 26 [39153019697384])
  - Brab - Bray, 1905-1920; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:27 (Box-folder 2:27, Box 2, Folder 27 [39153019697392])
  - Bradley Patent Butt Package Works, 1905; 1972.0001\SeriesI\Box2:28 (Box 2, Folder 28 [39153019697400], Box-folder 2:28)